Guide to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Vertical Files: Individuals ALBA.VF.002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Vertical Files: Individuals
1930-2011
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
ALBA.VF.002
11 Linear Feet
The Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) Vertical Files are a rich source for background information on the people, events and topics related to the ALBA collections in the Tamiment Library and include coverage of the International Brigades as well. The files contain a variety of documents such as newspaper clippings, flyers, brochures, biographical material, anniversary and exhibit programs, obituaries, and other items. Consult the folder list in this collection to find material on specific individuals. See the ALBA Vertical File on Subjects to find material related to topics and events.
Provenance
The provenance of the materials is varied; much of it came to the Tamiment Library with the original acquisition of ALBA collections in 2001. Other items were obtained through donations, arrangements with organizations, and ongoing collecting by Tamiment staff.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into one series: Series I: ALBA Individual Files. Folders are arranged alphabetically.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of files of printed ephemera such as biographical data, broadsides, brochures, bulletins, clippings, flyers, leaflets, obituaries, pamphlets, reprints, unpublished papers and other documents relating to a broad range of individuals connected in some way with the Abraham Lincoln Brigade. The bulk of the collection consists of files on individual Lincoln Brigade volunteers, but there are also files on Spanish participants in the Civil War, International Brigade volunteers from other nationality groups, journalists, visitors to Spain, and historians and others who have studied the conflict. (Some files include non-print items such as donor correspondence, typed notes, etc.)
Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, American; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Biography; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.; Pamphlets.; Programs (documents); Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Veterans.; Obituaries.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Participation, Jewish.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Personal narratives.; Bulletins.; Articles.; Clippings (information artifacts); Brochures.; Biographies.; Press releases.; Broadsides (notices); Reports.; Printed ephemera.; Fliers (printed matter); Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Abraham Lincoln Battalion; Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives
- Series I: ALBA Individual Files, 1
  - Aalto, William (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aalto, William: James Foss Manuscript (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Acevedo Mondragon, Servando (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Acken, Edgar Laurence (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Adams, Jack (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Ades, Bernard (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Adolphi, Hans (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Aguirre, Jose Antonio de (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Ain, Harry (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Alcorn, William P. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Aldanov, Mark Aleksandrovich, 1886-1957: "The Fifth Seal" (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Alexander, Alex (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Alexander, Bill (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Alexander, Frank Edward (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Allander, William (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Allen, Jay (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Alper, Marcus (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Altman, David (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Altman, Jack (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Alvarez del Vayo, Julio, 1891- (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Amatniek, Ernest (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Amery, Alfred (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Amlie, Hans (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Amsbury, Clifton (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Anderson, Casper (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Anderson, Mel (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Anderson, Ray (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Andreasen, Alfred (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Antiros, Panos (Peter) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Appleton, Owen (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Archer, Amos (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Arciero, Bernard (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Argirakis, Matthew (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Arion, Ernest (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Arvola, Frank (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Atomian, Lan (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Azana, Manuel, 1880-1940 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Babsky, Sidney I. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Bailey, Bill (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Bailey, Bill: Rifle (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Bailey, Howard (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Baker, William (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Balagurchik, Elias (Ylia) (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Balchowsky, Edward (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Baley, Barney (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Bard, Phil (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Barnett, James C. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Barr, Charles A. (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Barr, Herman (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Barr, Reuben (See Stojewa, Conrad H.) (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Barrett, Edward (includes letter from Spain) (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Barron, Sam (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Barrows, Ted (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Barsky, Edward K., 1897-1975 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Bates, Ralph, 1899-2000 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Battle, Thaddeus (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Baumler, Albert "Ajax" (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Bauza, Ulises (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Beebe, Vernold (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Belafonte, Harry (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Belau, Carl Gustav (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Bender, Ed (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Bender, Marion (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Benedet, Javier (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Benet, James ("Jim") (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Bennet, Millie (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Berg, Delmar ("Del") (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Berg, Nils (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Berkowitz, Norman (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Bermack, Richard (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Berman, Leo (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Bernard, John (Congressman) (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Bessie, Alvah Cecil, 1904-1985 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Bessie, Alvah Cecil, 1904-1985: Spanish Notebooks, transcribed (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Bessie, Dan (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Bethune, Norman (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Bevensee, Court (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Bianca, Joe (Bianco) (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Billings, Mark (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Bires, Albert (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Bjoze, Jack (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Black, Curtis (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Blackwell, Russell (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Blair, Fred, 1906-: "Our Brother Bill" (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Blair, John Clarence Alvie (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Blanc, Esther Silverstein, 1913- (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Block, Paul (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Bloom, Maurice (a.k.a. Maurice Winters) (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Boldini, Antonio (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Boehm, George (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Bolloten, Burnett, 1909-1987 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Bonetti, Frank (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Borer, Fred (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Borer, Wayland (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Borge, Victor (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Borghese, Junio Valerio (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Bottcher, Herman (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Botuck, Elijah (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Boudin, Leonard, 1912- (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Bowers, Claude Gernade, 1879-1958 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Bowie, John (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Bown, Vernon (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Bradley, Carl (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Braley, Roger Lancaster (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Brandt, Joseph, 1909-1997 (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Brandt, Willy, 1913-1992 (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Braxton, Milton (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Bridenthal, Ken (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Brier, Morris (Moishe) (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Briggs, Judson (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Brockway, Fenner, 1888-1988 (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Brodsky, George D., 1908- (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - Bronstein, Eugene David (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - Brooks, Christopher T. (Box 1, Folder 113)
  - Brostoff, Barney (Box 1, Folder 114)
  - Broue, Pierre (Box 1, Folder 115)
  - Brown, Archie, 1911-1990 (Box 1, Folder 116)
  - Brown, Ben C. (Box 1, Folder 117)
  - Brown, Frank (Box 1, Folder 118)
  - Brown, George, 1906-1937 (Box 1, Folder 119)
  - Brown, Tom (Box 1, Folder 120)
  - Browne, Richard (Box 1, Folder 121)
  - Buchanan, Cynthia (Box 1, Folder 122)
  - Budish, Nathan (Box 1, Folder 123)
  - Burch, Fernando (Box 1, Folder 124)
  - Burke, Paul (Box 1, Folder 125)
  - Burns, Helen (Box 1, Folder 126)
  - Burns, Paul, 1906 (?)-1996 (Box 1, Folder 127)
  - Busch, Dr. Irving (Box 1, Folder 128)
  - Buschak, Willy (Box 1, Folder 129)
  - Buska, Henry (Box 1, Folder 130)
  - Buturla, Frank (Box 1, Folder 131)
  - Cadden, J.E. (Box 1, Folder 132)
  - Caldarella, Michael (Box 1, Folder 133)
  - Caldwell, James (Box 1, Folder 134)
  - Caldwell, James: "Defense in University City" (Oversize) (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 19)
  - Cali, Frank (Box 1, Folder 135)
  - Callion, Walter P. (Box 1, Folder 136)
  - Cane, Lawrence, 1912-1976 (Box 1, Folder 137)
  - Cannon, Karl (Box 1, Folder 138)
  - Cannon, Walter Bradford, 1871-1945 (Box 1, Folder 139)
  - Cantos, Gregorio: "The Spanish People Fight On" (Box 1, Folder 140)
  - Capa, Robert, 1913-1954 (Box 1, Folder 141)
  - Carney, William (Box 1, Folder 142)
  - Carritt, Lizabeth (Box 1, Folder 143)
  - Carroll, Peter N. (Box 1, Folder 144)
  - Carroll, Will (Box 1, Folder 145)
  - Carsman, Sam (Box 1, Folder 146)
  - Carter, Barton (Nick) (Box 1, Folder 147)
  - Carter, Council Gibson (Box 1, Folder 148)
  - Carter, Edward A., d.1963 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cartier-Bresson, Henri (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Casals, Pablo, 1876-1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Casanova, Julian: Lecture (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Castro Costa, Juan (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Centelles, Agusti (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Cespedes Martinez, Felipe (a.k.a. Felipe Martinez) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Chaikin, George (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Chakin, Abraham (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Chase, Homer Bates (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Chase, Van (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Chipp, Herschel Browning (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Chirko, Frank (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Chisholm, Albert Edward (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Chisholm, Malcolm McDowell (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Chowan, Michael (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Cleveland, Roland (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Cloke, Richard (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Coad, Mack (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Coane, Robert (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Cobbs, Walter H. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Cogswell, Theodore (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Cohen, Henry (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Cohen, Milt (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Cohen, Morris; aka Israel Altman (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Collins, Leroy (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Colodny, Robert Garland (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Colon Gonzales, Gonzalo (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Colow, Maury (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Colver, Robert Loughlin (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Conway, Morris Michael (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Cook, Jerry (Gerald) (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Cookson, John Wilhelm, 1913-1938 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Cooper, Jack (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Cooper, Lou (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Copic, Vladimir, 1891-1939 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Corbin, Rudy (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Corrigan, John Horton (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Costanzo, Frank Carl (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Cox, James (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Cox, Thomas Jr. (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Craig, Curtis (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Crain, Harry Allen (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Cressman, Elmer (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Crome, Len (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Crook, David, 1910- (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Crook, David: Authobiography (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Crooks, Jimmy (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Crotto, Sidney (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Cueria y Orbit, Basilio (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Cullinen, George (See also Oversized) (Box 2, Folder 51, Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 20)
  - Cummins, Robert (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Curtis, Robert Lee (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Czitrom, Daniel J., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Czitrom, Louis, 1921-2011 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Dabelko, Steve (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Daduk, Stephen (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Dahl, Horld Evans (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Dal Col, Emilio (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Dallet, Joe, 1907-1937 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Danek, Thomas (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Day, John (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Day, Mary Gaerty (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - De La Mora, Constancia, 1906-1950 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - De La Mora, Constancia, 1906-1950 (Copies of Material from Fr...rika Martin Collection, ALBA #1) (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Del Rio, Elisio (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Delaney, Andrew (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Delehanty, John (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Delich, George (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Dellinger, David T, 1915-2004 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Delplanque, Paul: "The Spanish Revolution 1936-1937" (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - DeMaio, Anthony (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - DeVries, Lini M. (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Dhaga del Castillo, Jose (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Diaz, Jose (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Dicks, Walter (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Dickson, Nathaniel or Nathan (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Dikijian, John (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Dion, John (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Dobson, Harry (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Dollard, John, 1900- (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Dominguez Soler, Miguel (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Donegian, Bedros (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Donnelly, Charles (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Donowa, Arnold Bennett (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Doran, Dave, 1910-1938 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Doran, Lawrence Fant (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Dore, Mary (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Dorland, Norman Edward (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Dorsky, Leon (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Dos Passos, John, 1896-1970 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Doty, Bennett Jeffries, 1900- (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Doty, Bennett Jeffries, 1900-: Christopher Eger Research Material (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Dougher, Joe, b. 1897 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Doyle, Bob, 1916- (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Draper, George (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Drill, Joe (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Duff, Ethel Sage Colter (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Dukes, Larry Stratford (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Duncan, Lowell (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Durem, Ramen (Ramon) (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Durruti, Buenaventura, 1896-1936 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Duvalle, Pierre (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Dykstra, Matthew (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - Earl, Howard (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Eby, Cecil D. (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Ecker, Michael (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Ecstein, Sam (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Edwards, Albert (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - Edwards, Frank (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Ehrenberg, Mike (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Einstein, Albert (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Einstein, Carl, 1885-1940 (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Elliot, A. Randle: "Spain After Civil War" (1940) (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Eloesser, Leo (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Encarnacion, Omar G.: "Pinochet's Revenge: Spain Revisits its Civil War" (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Engert, Herman (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Entin, Alan (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - Entin, Bernard (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - Epailly, Raymond (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - Epstein, Jacob, 1880-1959 (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - Epstein, Melech (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - Epstein, Ruth (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - Erber, Ernest (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - Erkkila, John (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - Fahy, Jack Bradley (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - Fajans, Irving (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - Fajardo, Mark (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - Farkasovski, Joseph (Box 2, Folder 129)
  - Farrar, Max (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - Fasanella, Ralph (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - Fast, Howard: "Spain and Peace" (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - Feigen, Harry (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Fein, Richard (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - Feingersh, Francis (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Feldt, Orrin (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - Fellman, Harry and Sol (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Felsen, Milt, 1912- (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - Fernandez-Armesto, Felipe (Review of Beevor) (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Fernsworth, Lawrence A.: "Back to Spain," in Foreign Affairs (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - Feros, Antonio: "Civil War Still Haunts Spanish Politics," New York Times (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - Ferrer, Anton (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - Ferroggiaro, Jerry (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - Ferworker, Erna (Box 2, Folder 144)
  - Field, John (Box 2, Folder 145)
  - Field, Noel Haviland, 1904-1970: Archival Material in Hungary (Box 2, Folder 146)
  - Field, Ralph (Box 2, Folder 147)
  - Fine, Gene (Box 2, Folder 148)
  - Finkenberg, Harry (Box 2, Folder 149)
  - Finsen, Dr. Gunnar: Photo Collection (Box 2, Folder 150)
  - Fischer, Louis, 1896-1970 (Box 2, Folder 151)
  - Fisher, Harry, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 152)
  - Fisher, Ruth (Box 2, Folder 153)
  - Fishgold, Isidore (Irving) (Box 2, Folder 154)
  - Fishman, Morris S. (Box 2, Folder 155)
  - Fishman, Moses (Moe), 1916- (Box 2, Folder 156)
  - Fitzgerald, Daniel A. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Fitzsimmons, William (Fitz) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Flaherty Brothers (Charles, Frank and Edward) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Flato, Samuel: Polish Volume (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Flynn, Errol (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Foner, Henry (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Fontsere?, Carles (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Forbes, Hank (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Ford, Robert Preston (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Forester, Clarence (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Foster, William Z., 1881-1961: On Spain (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Foucek, Albert (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Foucek, George (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Fox, Ralph, 1900-1937 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Frait, Bill (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Frank, Willard C. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Franklin, Lynn Winterdale (U.S. Consul, Barcelona) (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Franklin, Samuel Nathan (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Franklin, Sidney, 1905-: "Bullfighter from Brooklyn" (1952; photocopy) (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Franklin, Zalmond D. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Frankson, Canute (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Fraser, Hamish (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Freed, Edward Milton (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Freeman, Jacob (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Freeman Fineberg, Helen (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Friedburg, Saul (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Friedman, Jack (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Friedman, Laurence (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Friedman, Martin, 1914-1966 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Frohman, Raleigh (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Frye, Peter (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Fuhrman, Murray (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Fuqua, Stephen (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Fuster-Chiner, Rafael (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Gandall, Bill (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Gardner, Ben (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Garland, Walter B. (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Gates, John, 1913- (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Gavin, Eugene Victor (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Gavin, Robert Owen (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Geiser, Carl (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Gellhorn, Martha, 1908-1998 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - George, Henry (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Gerassi, Fernando (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Gerassi, John (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Gerchik, Max (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Gerhartt, Julius (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Gerlach, John R. (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Gianfortoni, Joseph (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Gibbons, Danny (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Gibbons, Joe (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Gibbs, Theodore (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Gibelli, Primo (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Gilchrist, Alan (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Giler, Henry (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Girling, Elizabeth (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Gittelson, Lester (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Givney, John (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Gladnick, Robert (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Glaser, Ben (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Goddard, Howard Owen (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Goebbels, Joseph, 1897-1945 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Goff, Irving (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Gold, Irving (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Goldberg, Arthur J. (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Goldblatt, Sara (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Goldin Speigel, Irene (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Goldman, Anne Shuldiner (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Goldring, Benjamin (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Goldstein, Benjamin, 1910-1985 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Goldstein, Maynard (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Goldstein, Milt (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Goldwyn, Gerald (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Golomb, Ned (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Golzarri, Andrew (Andres) (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Gonshak, Sam (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Gonzalez, Manuel-Jesus (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Gordon, David, 1909-1973 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Gordon, Joseph, 1914-1942 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Gordon, Leo, 1915-1938 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Gordon, Louis (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Grachow, Leo (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Graeber, Ken (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Graham, Frank, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Graham, Meredith Sydnor (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Granat, Morris (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Grant, Samuel Andrew (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Grant, Walter Fairbanks (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Graver, William (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Green, Abner, 1913-1959 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Green, Nan (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Greenfield, Herman ("Hy") (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Greenspan, Sidney (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Greenstein, Jacob (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Greenstein, Joseph (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Grell, Fritz (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Gresham, William Lindsay (Wilkins) (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Grigas, Joseph (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Groden, Daniel Samuel (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Grodzki, Frank (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Gross, Nathan, 1914- (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Grossman, Henry (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Grossner, Samuel (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Grumet, Leonard (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Gruskin, Harold (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Guerra, Francisco Perez-Carral (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Gurevitz, Edgar A. (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Gurkow, Maurice (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Gurney, Jason: Crusade in Spain (excerpt) (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Gus (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Haggerty, George (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Hagis, Aris (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Hakam, Harry (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Haley, Jonathan Clifford Jr. (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Hall, Charles (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Hall, Philip E (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - Hall, Yolanda (Bobby) (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - Halonen, Oiva (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - Halpern, Alvin (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - Hamill, Pete, 1935- (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - Hampkins, Peter (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - Hannigan, Walter (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - Hargrave, Roger (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Harriman, Manny (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - Harrington, Bill (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Harris, Aaron (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Harris, Albert Lyonel, 1907- (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - Harris, Sydney, 1916- (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Harvey, George (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Harvey, William (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - Hashooley, Jack (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - Haskell, Daniel Irving (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - Hausman, Carl, 1953- (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - Hautaneimi, Joe (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - Hayes, Helen, 1900-1993 (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - Hayes, Thomas (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - Haynes, John, "The Myth of Premature Antifascism" (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Haywood, Harry, b.1898 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Heagney, Frank (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Hecht, Joe (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Heinricher, Stan (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Hellmann, Lillian, 1905-1984 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Hemingway, Ernest, 1899-1961 I [see also Milton Wolff file] (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Hemingway, Ernest, 1899-1961 II [see also Milton Wolff file] (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Hemingway, Ernest, 1899-1961: New Masses (Oversize) (Oversize Shared ALBA VF OS, Folder 21)
  - Hendler, Max (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Hendra, Tony (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Hendrickson, George (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Hene, Julius (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Henry, Don (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Hernandez Rodriguez, Oscar (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Herndon, Milton (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Herrick, William, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Hibbert, Phyllis (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Higgins, John, 1954- (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Highkin, Joseph (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Hilkevitch, Aaron (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Hilsenrad, Elias (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Hilton, Ronald, 1911-2007 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Hinman, Luke (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Hobbs, Everett (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Hobsbawm, Eric J., 1917-: On Spanish Civil War (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Hochberg, Emanuel (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Hodge, Velmar Edward (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Hoff, Harold Smith (d. 1998) (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Hoffman, Heinz (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Holburn, Harry (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Holtzclaw, Leonard Martin (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Honeycombe, John Gordon (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Hopper, Dale (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Horowitz, Sidney (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Howe, Irving (Box 4, Folder 29)